



+27 79 502 0767 (SA)



alan1kane@gmail.com



South Africa & Zanzibar



www.linkedin.com/in/alan-kane-7a05a28

COMPETENCIES

New Hotel Developments

Strategic Business Marketing

Financial Management

Operations Management

Hotel openings and Re-developments

ALAN KANE

HOSPITALITY SPECIALIST - AFRICA.

General Manager

Seacliff Resort and Spa, Zanzibar, East Africa.

Period: 2018 to present Web: <u>seacliffzanzibar.com</u>

Sea Cliff Resort and Spa, a 5 star luxury hotel located on a cliff overlooking the Indian Ocean, nestling on the Northern-West coast of Zanzibar, just twenty-five minutes from the historical Stone Town city.

Project Manager / Opening Manager

Treasures Suites & Conference Hotel, Abuja, Nigeria.

Period: 2016 - 2018 Web: www.treasures.ng

Upmarket 44 Bedroom Conference Centre.

General Manager

Protea Hotel (now Bon Hotel) Abuja, Nigeria.

Period: 2014 - 2016

Web: www.bonhotels.com

The BON Hotel is nestled close to Abuja's city centre. A 4-Star luxury hotel in close proximity to both the British & Irish Embassies.

COMPETENCIES

Supply Chain / Distribution

Transportation / Logistics

Sustainable and Profitable Growth

Continuous Improvement (CI)

Hotel Construction projects

Project Management

SHE & Risk Management

Leadership & Mentoring

EDUCATION

Hospitality Supervision
Diploma.
American Hotel and Motel
Association. 1991.

Matriculation completed at Bracken High School, Johannesburg, South Africa. 1987.

Software skills:
MS Office Suite (Word/Excel/
Powerpoint/Illustrator)
MS Server,
HIS, Opera, Fidelio.
Micros,
Great General Systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Manager

Zebula Golf Estate & Spa, Limpopo Province, South Africa.

Period: 2012 - 2014 Web: <u>zebula.co.za</u>

Situated in the Waterberg Mountains of Limpopo and a mere 2 hours drive from Johannesburg. This impressive 1600 hectare Golf Estate and Spa is stocked with wild game.

General Manager

Continental Outdoor Media (now JCDecaux SA), Malawi.

Period: 2009 - 2012

Web: jcdecauxafrica.com

Continental Outdoor is an outdoor advertising company that operates in 16 countries in sub-Saharan Africa, with more than 37000 out door advertising panels on display.

General Manager

Tribe Hotel, Nairobi, Kenya.

Period: 2007 - 2009 Web: tribe-hotel.com

The Tribe Hotel, is a 5 star luxury hotel located approximately 25 km from Nairobi's International Airport - Jomo Kenyatta International Airport (NBO).

Regional General Manager

Ryalls Hotel, Blantyre, Malawi (Protea Hotels Group)

Period: 2001- 2007 Web: <u>www.marriott.com</u>

The Ryalls Hotel, is a 4 star luxury hotel located in the central business district of Blantyre in Malawi and 16 Km's from Chileka Airport.

EDUCATION

Self Development Courses:

Interaction Management -Carlton Hotel.

Hospitality Supervision.

Profitable Standards.

Financial Accounting.

Training - Protea Hotels Minimum Standards.

Yield Management.

Paramedics.

First Aid.

Fire Fighting.

Protea Hotels Facilitator.

BOARDS / COMMITTEE

Board Member of the Zanzibar Association of Tourism Investors. Dec 2020 to present.

Malawi Tourism Board - Marketing Associates Committee, 2002 -2005.

Honourable Secretary of the Golf Union of Malawi. 2006.

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Manager

Protea Hotel, Karridene Beach, Durban, South Africa.

Period: 1997 - 2001

Web: www.marriott.com

The Protea Hotel, is a 3 star beach hotel being the water park at Durban South Beach being 20 minutes away from Durban CBD and 45 minutes away from the King Shaka International

Airport.

Food & Beverage Manager

The San Lameer Resort Hotel and Spa, Durban, South Africa.

Period:1995 - 1997

Web: www.sanlameer.co.za

The San Lameer Resort Hotel & Spa is located on the southern most coastline of Kwa-Zulu Natal and 1.5 hours from Durban.

Various positions

The Carlton Hotel (Westin Hotels), South Africa.

Period:1988 - 1995

KEY PERFORMANCE INDEX'S

Human Resource Management:

Ensure the wellbeing, development and recognition of all personnel which is measured by mentoring and frequent feedback. Strengthening our HR team by ensuring they take steps to develop personnel internally.

Customer Service and Stakeholder Management:

Ensure the wellbeing, service and environment during gusts stay is of an exceptional standard done by ensuring customers feedback is reviewed and queries attended to immediately. Drive training and development to ensure improvement of customer communication, services and customer re-tension ensuring long term business sustainability and profits.

PERSONAL

Status: Married

Family: 2 (13 & 16 years old).

Place of Birth: Bearsden, Glasgow,

Scotland, UK.

DOB: 17 September 1969.

Health: Excellent

Nationality: South African & British.

Address: Parktown North,

Gauteng, South Africa.

Languages: English & Afrikaans

(Fully Bilingual), French (Fair).

Valid Passports: Yes, both British

and South African.

Interests: Golf, Music, IT, Walking.

REFERENCES

Gavin Simpson -Holiday Holdings - Group MD and Founder Owner - Zebula Owner - Hertz SA

Rob Scharar Owner FCA Corporation Owner of Blantyre Hotels Limited -Protea Hotel Ryalls

Josef Hermans
Hospitality consultant to FCA
Corporation
Prior Lecturer at University of
Houston - Texas

Contact numbers available upon request.

KEY PERFORMANCE INDEX'S

Operations Management:

Assist Board Executives in obtaining set goals in line with company policies. Balance Revpar with ARR to ensure neither loses value or effectiveness and the continued Revpar growth allowing for effective cost management. Assess revenue collection systems and implementing documentation control processes. Constantly monitored criteria, to ensure the growth of the business while maintaining the correct margins and satisfaction levels.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

My experience extends beyond that of a traditional GM in that I have been involved in the development and launch of new Hotels from scratch overseeing the design, development and construction phases. I have ensured that new Hotels are opened on the planned date and were able to deliver the required level of service. In addition I also have a flair for the correct selection of interior finishes and furnishing choices.

Zanzibar: Seacliff Resort and Spa: For the past 2 years I have had the best financial results, eclipsing previous financial years, while also improving standards and relationships with new operators.

Nigeria: Fully renovated the first hotel in Asokoro for Protea Group.

Kenya: Oversaw the opening of a new 5 Star Hotel - The Tribe Hotel.

Malawi: Ryalls hotel redevelopment which is still regarded as the best hotel in Blantyre Malawi. Successful conceptualisation of the "21 Grill on Hannover" restaurant in Blantyre Malawi which is still the best restaurant in the City.